Guide to the Ricardo Sánchez Papers, 1941-1995
Department of Special Collections
- SERIES IX: Audiovisual materials.
  - Subseries #2. Audiocassettes
    - 12-15-85, Poets of Tejas, #3 (Box 120, Folder 60)
    - Presbyterian Conference 1/28/87, San Antonio, incl. Ricardo Sánchez (Box 120, Folder 61)
    - Program #1 Raices y Ritmos - Roots and Rythms, introduction and Panorama: 28 min side 1; 27:00 side 2 (Box 120, Folder 62)
    - Rancheras del Recuerdo... (Box 120, Folder 63)
    - Rikard's Party (Box 120, Folder 64)
    - Rikard's Party (Box 120, Folder 65)
    - Frank Rodarte (Box 120, Folder 66)
    - Rodarte Tacoland (Box 120, Folder 67)
    - Para Ricardo, te aprecia, Maria Rosas, Ecos del Coquei [?], Junio 11, 83 (Box 120, Folder 68)
    - San Antonio Ears (CBS) - Poem for CBS Take 1 (Box 120, Folder 69)
    - "SáNCHEZ" Readings of by Soto, Joe Bruchal, Bersen Brugge, Javier Pacheco (Box 120, Folder 70)
    - "SáNCHEZ" Readings of by Sandra Estenes 31:10; Simon Ortiz 27:30 (Box 120, Folder 71)
    - Readings de "SáNCHEZ": IWASAKI 30:16; Tony Parra 16:20; Tony Parra 15:30 (Box 120, Folder 72)
    - Ricardo Sánchez 35:30 (Box 120, Folder 73)
    - Ricardo Sánchez 35:30 (Box 120, Folder 74)
    - Ricardo Sánchez 35-27-93 (Box 120, Folder 75)
    - Mr. Sánchez 2/17/85 (Box 120, Folder 76)
    - Ricardo Sánchez 35:30 (Box 120, Folder 77)
    - Ricardo Sánchez interview (Box 121, Folder 78)
    - Poesia de Ricardo Sánchez, Spanish only, side 1; English Language only, side 2, Poetry by Ricardo Sánchez (Box 121, Folder 79)
    - R. Sánchez 9-16-84 (Box 121, Folder 80)
    - Interview of Ricardo Sánchez (Box 121, Folder 81)
    - Ricardo Sánchez (Box 121, Folder 82)
    - Ricardo S[ánchez] (Box 121, Folder 83)
    - KDNA interview, Ricardo Sánchez with Ricardo Garcia (Rough Cut), May 19, 1993 (Box 121, Folder 84)
    - Teresa Sánchez. Mr. Delgado 3/18/86 (Box 121, Folder 85)
    - Sancho Show 25 (Box 121, Folder 86)
    - Script Conference, Rio Dorado, 9/19/87; Ed Gonzales, Ricardo Sánchez, Pleas[ [?] McNeel at Papernacks y mas (Box 121, Folder 87)
    - Leslie Silko poems and story 39:20; Frank Chin "The Lone Ranger" 15:30 (Box 121, Folder 88)
    - Leslie Silko poems and story 39:20; Frank Chin "The Lone Ranger" 15:30 (Box 121, Folder 89)
    - Leslie Silko poems and story 39:20; Frank Chin "The Lone Ranger" 15:30 (Box 121, Folder 90)
    - Sonando-Viva la Grima-Como Olvidarte-El Extranjero (Box 121, Folder 91)
    - Poetry Southwest rec. 7/10/80 (Ricardo Sánchez readings) (Box 121, Folder 92)
    - Las Quatro Esquinas del Tango: Tangos Poemisados (Box 121, Folder 93)
    - Taylor Lecture, Feb. 7, 1973 (Box 121, Folder 94)
    - Teatro Mexco, Junio 13. 84. grab. Adrian O. Bernal (sides 1& (Box 121, Folder 95)
    - Teatro Mexco, Junio 13. 84. Grabacion por Adrian. Bernal (side 3); Paginas de mi Vida. A Bernal/ Como Olvidarte?/sonando/El Amor no Llego/Este Dia (Box 121, Folder 96)
    - Los Tocotines (Box 121, Folder 97)
    - [Twelve] XII Trav[elers] Review Committee: Oct. 16 1989, Nov. 13, 1989, Nov. 22, 1989 (?) (Box 121, Folder 98)
    - [Twelve] XII Trav[elers] Review Committee: Dec. 6, 1989; Dec. 13, 1989; Mar. ?, 1990 (Box 121, Folder 99)
    - USSR Planetary Peace; Jazz in New York-XMAS (Box 121, Folder 100)
    - KTEP, Vision Fronterica, 11 Nov. 90 (Box 121, Folder 101)
    - Wet Willie, "Dixie Rock"; Peter Tosh "Legalize It (Box 121, Folder 102)
    - WDAI Interview 5/24/84, Ricardo Sánchez (Box 121, Folder 103)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #1 (Box 121, Folder 104)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #2 (Box 121, Folder 105)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #3 (Box 121, Folder 106)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #4 (Box 121, Folder 107)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #5 (Box 121, Folder 108)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #6 (Box 121, Folder 109)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #7 (Box 121, Folder 110)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #8 (Box 121, Folder 111)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #9 (Box 121, Folder 112)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #10 (Box 121, Folder 113)
    - Unlabeled/Unidentified #11 (Box 121, Folder 114)
    - Mini-Cassette: Semana de la Raza 3/93 @WSU: sides 1) and 2) Nepthali Talent show (Box 121, Folder 115)
    - Mini-Cassette: Semana de la Raza 3/93 @WSU: sides 3) Talent show and 4) (Box 121, Folder 116)
    - Mini-Cassette: Semana de la Raza 3/93 @WSU: sides 5) and 6) (Box 121, Folder 117)
    - Mini-Cassette: Semana de la Raza 3/93 @WSU: Semana Banquet (Box 121, Folder 118)
    - Mini-Cassette: Interview/May 4.. [?] (Box 121, Folder 119)
    - Mini-Cassette: International Tribal Trial, San Francisco, Oct. 1992 (Box 121, Folder 120)
    - Mini-Cassette: 3 Oct 92 Internat'l Tribunal, SF, Ca, R. Sánchez (Box 121, Folder 121)
    - Mini-Cassette: Interview... includes note from Mike Jones (Box 121, Folder 122)
  - Subseries #3. Odd-sized audiovisual materials
    - Oversized Video Tape: Chávez celebration [?] (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Oversized Video Tape: Chávez celebration [?] (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Oversized Video Tape: Johnny Gi-Tar Gutierrez [? ] CTN 6:30 pm (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Oversized Video Tape: Sánchez Interview (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Film Reel: Sánchez Goody; Salt Lake City; Washington State University Sports Information - M. Peyou (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Film Reel: Salt Lake City: Poetic Despedida at Time Winto Gallery, Sánchez family adios (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Film Reel: "Ski Trip" (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Film Reel: Unlabeled (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - 45" records (2 copies): Frank Rodarte and The Alamo All Stars, "Unidos" (Box 123, Folder 9)
PROMINENT OR FREQUENTLY-MENTIONED INDIVIDUALS AND ORGANIZATIONS
Individuals:
Ackley, Randall -Sánchez's professor/advisor in Union Graduate School Ph.D. program
Acosta, Manuel Gregorio -artist
Aguirre, Rafael Hinojos
Almaeida, Jose -scholar
Anaya, Rudolfo -author
Andouard-Labarthe, Elyette -French scholar
Angelou, Maya -poet
Atencio, Tomás -Chicano scholar
Bacchiega, Franca -Italian scholar
Barrios, Greg -poet
Binder, Wolfgang -German scholar
Blackerby, Ric -artist
Blaine, Julien -French scholar
Broyles, Yolanda -Chicana scholar
Bruce-Novoa, Juan -Chicano scholar
Bruhac, Joe -artist
Burciaga, José Antonio -artist
Camarillo, Cecilio García -Chicano scholar
Candelaria, Cordelia -Chicana scholar
Cárdenas de Dwyer, Carlota -Chicana scholar
Carrillo, Leonardo -Chicano scholar
Christensen, Paul -author, scholar, editor
Cisneros, Henry -San Antonio mayor
Clinton, Bill -president
Cody, Jim -artist
Cuellar, José ("Dr. Loco") -musician and scholar
de Hoyos, Angela -poet
de la Fuente, Patricia -Chicana scholar
de la Torre, Alfredo
de León, Nephtalí -artist and poet
del Castillo, Moises Espino -author
Delgado, Abelardo ("Lalo")-poet
Durán, Felipe -scholar
Duarte, Pete -prison poet?
Gueder, Pat -scholar
Gilb, Dagoberto -novelist
Goldsmith, Andrew -student of Sánchez, scholar
Goodman, Leonard
Gordon, Roxy
Gorski, Hedwig -scholar
Guerrero, Andrés
Guerrero, Zarco (Adolfo) -artist
Gutierrez y Falcon, Alfredo -scholar
Haddox, John -scholar
Hancock, Joel -scholar
Hetherington, M. S. (Sue) -scholar
Hillman, Grady -publisher
Hirsch, Dena
Houser, John -artist
Kanellos, Nicolas -publisher
Keene, Tom -poet
Kirkwood, Porter -activist
Kissinger, C. Clark -activist
Kuzminsky, K.K. -artist
Laufer, Bill
Lauritsen, Arthur -publisher
Lewis, Rob -author, poet, publisher
Lomelí, Francisco -scholar
Lopez, Roy
Lynch, Peggy Zuleika
Mann, Dana -student of Sánchez
Marble, Guy -editor of prison newspaper The Echo
Marcus, Hal -artist
Mares, Andrés
Martín-Rodríguez, Manuel M.
Martínez, Ernesto P. -artist
Montoya, José -artist, poet, musician
Morales, Travis -activist
Morton, Carlos -writer
Norman, Arthur -scholar
Otego y Gasca, Felipe (Phil) -scholar and critic
Ortiz, Simón
Pacheco, Javier -musician and poet
Padilla, Rudy
Parker, Mary ("Magdalene")
Peña, Juan José
Perez, Reimundo "Tigre" -poet
Piercey, Jim -activist
Rangel, Andrew
Rocard, Marcienne -French scholar
Rodríguez, Juan Antonio
Romero, Rolando
Rosas, Carlos -artist
Rossow, Josué Ybarra
Salinas, Raul ("Tapón") -prison poet
Sánchez, Trinidad -poet
Soto, Gary -poet
Taylor, Chuck -writer, publsiher
Taylor, Pat Ellis ("Pat Little Dog") -writer
Tello, Victor
Thurston, Linda -activist
Tilton, John -took over Paperbacks... y más bookstore
Valdez, Jim -artist
Vento, Arnoldo C. -scholar
Willard, William
Wilson, Gene-K (artist)
Zimmerman, Enid -scholar
Institutions and Organizations:
Academia de la Nueva Raza
Arte Público Press
Canto Al Pueblo
El Paso Community College
El Paso Herald-Post
El Paso Public Library
National Association for Chicano Studies
National Endowment for the Arts
National Interreligious Task Force on Criminal Justice
People of Color Task Force on Criminal Justice
Refuse and Resist! (La Resistencia)
San Antonio Express-News
ViAztlán